In Unity each script contains a definition
Unity では各々のスクリプトはクラス定義が含まれます。
for a class. If we were to extend our
もし変数を箱、関数を機械
metaphor where variables are boxes
に例えるならば
and functions are machines then classes
クラスはこの箱や機械がおかれている
would be the factories that these boxes
工場にあたります。
and machines are in. You may have noticed
すでにお気づきかもしれませんが
that scripts from other tutorials have
他のチュートリアルからのスクリプトは
keyword class near the top.
クラス キーワードが上の方に表示されていました。
Unity automatically puts this line in
Unity は C# スクリプトを作成するとき、
the script for you when you create a new
これらを自動的に行に含めます。
C# script. This is implicit in Javascript,
Javascript ではこれは暗黙的です。
meaning that you won't see the definition
すなわち、定義は表示されませんが、
but Unity still treats the contents of
Unity はスクリプトの内容を
this script as a class.
クラスとして扱います。
This class shares the same name as the
クラスはスクリプトが含まれるファイルと同じ
script it is in. This is very important,
名称です。これは重要なことであり、
and if you change the name of one you
ファイル名かクラス名のいずれかを変更した場合
must change the name of the other.
他方の名前を変更する必要があります。
It is often best not to change the name of
クラスのスクリプトの名前は変更しないのがベストであり、
scripts of classes unless you absolutely
絶対にやる必要がないかぎりやめておくべきです。
have to. So try to name your script
このため、スクリプトの名前は
sensibly when you create it.
作成する時点で意味のあるものとして下さい。
The class is a container for variables
クラスはそれが提供する変数および
and functions and provides, amongst other
関数のコンテナであり、
things a nice way to group things
連携して動作するものをグループ化する
that work together.
メリットなどあります。
They are an organisational tool in
オブジェクト指向プログラミング、
something known as Object Oriented Programming,
略して OOP とよばれるものの
or OOP for short.
整理のためのツールです。
The solution and core of OOP is to split the
OOP のソリューションおよびコア部分は
script up in to multiple scripts,
複数のスクリプトに分割されています。
each one taking a single role.
そして各々がひとつの役割をもっています。
Classes should therefore be dedicated
このため、クラスはひとつのタスク専用とすべきです。
to one task. In this example we have a script
このサンプルでは複数の異なるタスクを
that handles a number of different tasks
ハンドリングするスクリプトがあるので
so we should split it up in to three
より容易に管理するために
shorter scripts to make it easier to manage.
3 つの短いスクリプトに分割します。
This script, for example, handles an
例えば、このスクリプトでは
inventory, movement and shooting.
インベントリ、動作、撃つ動作などハンドリングします。
Here's the script in action when
キューブにスクリプトをアタッチした場合
attached to a cube.
の動作はこのようになります。
We can drive it around, we can shoot
動き回したり、小さなオブジェクトを
some small objects
発射したり
and we can keep track of items in our
またアイテムのインベントリ管理をすることが出来ます。
inventory. But this is all contained
しかし、これらはすべてひとつの
within a single character script.
キャラクタースクリプトの中で管理されます。
What we should be doing is organising
これらをインベントリの中で整理することを
this into inventory, movement and shooting
していく必要があり、インベントリ、動作、発射
as three separate classes.
3 つの異なるクラスで管理します。
So if I switch to another scene,
このためシーンを切替すると、
which looks identical, then the cube
シーンは完全に同じですが、キューブに
has scripts which handle each of these things
アタッチされたスクリプトは別々のスクリプトに
individually. This makes these
分割されています。これにより
scripts easier to manager, easier to read
スクリプトの管理はより容易になり
and more efficient to write.
コーディング効率も上がります。
Let's take a look at the use of a class.
クラスの使用方法をみていきます。
In this example we have our inventory class.
この例ではインベントリクラスからみていきます。
And within that we have a subclass
この中にはさらにサブクラスがあり、
called Stuff. We create the class here
Stuff という名前です。クラスをこのときに作成して
and it contains three integer variables.
それは 3 つの integer 変数をもちます。
One for bullets, one for grenades
ひとつは弾丸、ひとつは手榴弾、
and one for rockets.
ひとつはロケットのための変数す。
We then create an instance of this class,
次にこのクラスのインスタンス
known as an object, down here.
すなわちオブジェクトと呼ばれるものをこの下の方に作成してます。
We give it the data type, which is
次にデータ型、
effectively the name of the class
要するにクラス名を与えて
and then we give it a name and we say
new 構文を使用して
new, and again reuse the name of the class.
再びクラスの名前を再度入力します。
The brackets on the end of the name of
名前の最後にある {} は
of the class imply that a constructor
コンストラクタが使用されていることを
is being used. A constructor is a function
示します。コンストラクタとは
that you can use to give default values
クラスの変数にデフォルトの値を
to the variables in your class,
使用できる、などいくつか実行できる
amongst other tasks that they can perform.
タスクを持った関数です。
For example, we might setup a default constructor.
例えばデフォルトのコンストラクタをセットアップしてみましょう。
Here we've given default values to each
ここでは各々のクラスの integer 変数に
of the integer variables inside our class.
デフォルト値を与えてみました。
This means that instead of being initialised
すなわち 0 の値をデフォルトとする代わりに
as 0 they'll be given a default value
1 の値による初期化が行われます。
of 1. What we can also do is write
もうひとつ出来ることとしては
our own constructor that allows us to set
自身のコンストラクタを作成して
parameters for those variables.
これらの変数の引数をセットすることです。
So, for example, we might say,
例えば、
public Stuff and then inside the brackets
public 変数の Stuff を書いたうえで
create some parameters.
{} の中でいくつかの引数を作成することが出来ます。
Then what we might do is assign our
そこで出来ることとしては変数をこれらの引数に
variables to these parameters
割り当てることです。
This means that when we create an object
つまり自身のクラスのオブジェクトまたはインスタンスを
or an instance of our class down here
この下の方で作成した場合
we can now use the brackets to define
{} によってそれらのデフォルト値が
what those default values will be.
何かを定義することが出来ます。
So we know that if we put in an integer
このため integer の後に
then a comma, an integer then a comma,
カンマを入力すれば、
we'll be defining exactly what those
クラスのインスタンスでの
variables within this instance of the
変数が何を定義しているかはっきりと
class will be. For example we may have 50
定めることが出来ます。例えば 50 個 の弾丸があるとして
bullets, and you can see that monodevelop
MonoDevelop によって
is helping me figure out what I'm doing
入力するごとに補助が表示される
by telling me as I write them
ことが確認できます。
and let's say we've got 5 grenades
例えば 5 個の手榴弾があり、
and we've got 5 rockets.
5 個のロケットがあったとします。
A few things to note about constructors.
コンストラクタについて覚えておくべきことがいくつかあります。
First off the name of the constructor
ひとつめの点は、コンストラクタの名前は
is always the name of the class.
つねにクラス名と同じということです。
Constructors never have a return type,
コンストラクタには戻り値は存在せず、
not even void.
void でさえありません。
A class can have multiple different constructors
クラスには複数の異なったコンストラクタを持たせることが出来ますが
but only one of them gets called when an
オブジェクトが初期化されるときにコール出来るのは
object is initialised. For example our
そのうちのひとつだけです。例えば
first constructor sets up values for
最初のコンストラクタの場合は
these three integers. But what if we had
これら 3 つの integer の値をセットアップします。しかし、
more values. Let's put in a float for how
変数がより多くあった場合を考えてみます。float 変数を
much fuel we're carrying.
追加して、積載燃料の量を表すものとしてみます。
Now currently this constructor does not
現時点ではコンストラクタはこのための変数を
setup a value for that. But we could setup
セットアップしません。しかしもうひとつのコンストラクタをセットアップして、
another constructor to do that job for us.
この機能を実現することが出来ます。
And then if we use the parameters setup
さらにこのコンストラクタでセットアップされた
in this constructor, what we'll see is that
引数を使用すれば
this constructor will be used to setup
このコンストラクタにより新しいオブジェクトを
our new object. So if I make one that has,
セットアップするのに使用されることが確認できます。このため弾丸を表すものや燃料を
for example the bullets, and then
示す変数を
a float for the fuel.
持たせることが出来ます。
Now that I have a separate constructor
別のコンストラクタが出来たところで、
what I can do is create an instance
インスタンスを作成して
and use a different constructor based upon
インスタンスに入れた引数にもとづいて
what parameters I put in to that instance.
異なったコンストラクタを使用することが出来ます。
So I can say new Stuff and this time
例えば new Stuff と書いて、
I can say, for example, 50 bullets and
今回は 50 個の弾丸と
1.5 amount of fuel.
1.5 リットルのl燃料があると宣言することが出来ます。
Now, this instance of the class is going
次に、このクラスのインスタンスは
to use this constructor because the
引数の数がマッチするためコンストラクタが
parameters match. Whereas my other instance
使用されます。逆にクラスのコンストラクタもうひとつのインスタンスは
of the class we use this constructor
引数の数がマッチするこっちの
because those parameters match.
コンストラクタを使用します。
So you can do a lot of different things
コンストラクタでは色んなことを
with constructors and you can have multiple
行うことが出来て同じクラスに複数の
different constructors for the same class.
コンストラクタをもたせることが出来ます。
So hopefully you can see how useful classes
これでクラスがいかに便利なものであるか、
are at organising your data when creating
ゲームを作成するうえでデータの整理に役立つか伝えられたので、、
games, and it's recommended that you think
スクリプトがどのようにレイアウトさせるか
through how your scripts are going
考え抜くことを推奨します。
to be laid out, before you go and just
逆に何も考えずに
write one huge class that has loads of
巨大なひとつのクラスの中に異なるものが
different things in it.
ごちゃまぜに混ざっていると大変です。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)